Where reality is experienced differently.
The most common psychotic disease is schizophrenia
Which I have also made a separate video about.
But there are also others such as
reactive psychosis that is a temporary psychosis
triggered by stressful events,
Schizoa -efficient syndrome
that combines schizophrenia symptoms with mood swings,
delusions syndrome, giving prolonged
delusions without other psychotic symptoms.
And then there is something called birth psychosis.
It is a rare type of psychosis that can occur shortly after childbirth.
Psychosis is not
a disease in itself without rather a group of symptoms that may
be part of several different mental health conditions.
It is important to understand that a psychosis is something that can hit
Anyone and there is nothing the person himself has chosen.
Symptoms may occur as a result of frightening or severe events,
other diseases or use of certain types of drugs.
There is help to get and with the right support and treatment, many can live
A good life despite periods of psychosis.
But what exactly does it mean to have a
Psychosis and what is it causing?
Heredity.
If there are psychotic diseases in the family, the risk of developing a psychosis may be higher.
Trauma and experiences of trauma, especially
During childhood, can increase the risk of psychosis later in life.
High stress levels or significant life changes
may trigger psychotic episodes in some individuals.
Prolonged sleep deprivation and even psychiatric
condition such as bipolar disorder and schizophrenia.
It is important to note that psychosis is not always linked to another illness
and can be triggered by an isolated event.
In addition, a combination of different factors can contribute to the development of psychosis
People who experience a psychosis can sometimes feel an excessive
rising despair or hopelessness, which can lead them
to consider very serious and harmful actions against themselves.
It is of utmost importance to seek professional help and support immediately.
If you or someone you know, these tanks or emotions are experiencing.
You can contact a psychiatric reception, a regular emergency room
Or if there is an acute risk of self -harm behavior.
Call 112
I hope you have
Learned a little more about what a psychosis is for something.
Feel free to subscribe to the channel.